https://stcharlesspine.com/privacy-policy/

Make An Appointment
558 St. Charles Drive | Suite 200 Thousand Oaks, CA 91360
(805) 379-2322
HomeAbout UsMeet Our ProvidersErik C. Spayde, MDJonathan Rice, MPA, PA-CJason Hartman, DOServicesMinimally Invasive Spine SurgeryArtificial Disc ReplacementVertebroplasty or KyphoplastyXLIF®Epidural Steroid InjectionsStem Cell TherapyImaging Services (MRI)Patient FormsFor SpaydeFor HartmanEducationTestimonialsFrom Patients of Dr. SpaydeTeleMed Consult
St Charles Spine Institute
Privacy Policy
We are sensitive to protecting the privacy of our website visitors. Our Privacy Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect and use the personal information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our site.What Information Do We Collect?When you visit our websites or other media, you may provide us with two types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis and website or media use information collected on an aggregate basis as you browse our website or media content. If you just browse our site and don’t interact with any forms or online services, you browse anonymously. Information that identifies you personally — such as your name, address, phone number and email address — is not collected as you browse.1. Personal Information You Choose to ProvideRegistration Information.If you choose, you may provide us information about yourself, your firm or company when you register for certain services, or register for email newsletters and alerts.Email Information.If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses.2. Website Use InformationSimilar to other websites, our site and other media content utilize a standard technology called “cookies” (see explanation below, “What Are Cookies?”) and Web server logs to collect information about how our website and media content are used. Information gathered through cookies and Web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our website, and the websites visited just before and just after our website. We, our advertisers and ad serving companies, if any, may also use small technology or pieces of code to determine which content users have seen and how users responded to them.How Do We Use the Information That You Provide to Us?Broadly speaking, we use personal information for purposes of administering our activities, providing customer service and making available other products and services to you. Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our website, new services and special offers we think you will find valuable. You may notify us at any time if you do not wish to receive these offers.What Are Cookies?A cookie is a very small text document, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier. When you visit a website, that site’s computer asks your computer for permission to store this file in a part of your hard drive specifically designated for cookies. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser’s preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites. Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies that originate from their sites. We have no access or control over those cookies.How Do We Use Information We Collect from Cookies?As you use our website, the site uses its cookies to differentiate you from other users. In some cases, we also use cookies to prevent you from seeing unnecessary information or requiring you to log in more than is necessary for security. Cookies, in conjunction with our Web server’s log files, allow us to calculate the aggregate number of people visiting our website and which parts of the site are most popular. This helps us gather feedback in order to constantly improve our website and better serve our customers. Cookies do not allow us to gather any personal information about you and we do not generally store any personal information that you provided to us in your cookies.How Do We Protect Your Information?How Do We Secure Information Transmissions?Email is not recognized as a secure medium of communication. For this reason, we request that you do not send private information to us by email. Some of the information you may enter on our website may be transmitted securely via Secure Sockets Layer SSL, 128 bit encryption services. Pages utilizing this technology will have URLs that start with HTTPS instead of HTTP. Please contact us if you have any questions or concerns.Health and Medical Information.Certain health and medical information about you is protected under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (“HIPAA”) and applicable state law. This information may be provided by you online or offline, or may be collected by us from other methods such as through a health care provider. We protect covered health and medical information as required by HIPAA and applicable state law. Similarly, we may use covered health and medical information as permitted by HIPAA and applicable state law.In the event of any conflict between our HIPAA Notice of Privacy Practices and this website Privacy Policy, the terms of our HIPAA Notice of Privacy Practices shall control.Certain Disclosures.We may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the law or comply with legal process served on us or affiliated parties; (b) protect and defend our rights and property, our site, the users of our site, and/or our affiliated parties; (c) act under circumstances to protect the safety of users of our site, us, or third parties.What About Other Websites Linked to Our Website?We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our website nor the information or content contained therein. Often links to other websites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that may be useful to the users of our website.Please remember that when you use a link to go from our website to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link on our website, is subject to that website’s own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.Your Consent.By using our website or our other media content, you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our website to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it.
Patient EducationLearn more about a variety of minimally invasive surgical procedures and non-surgical treatment options for spine-related pain and conditions.
Watch Our Videos
Patient FormsFor your convenience, please print and fill out all applicable forms and present them to the front desk when you arrive for your appointment.
Download Patient Forms
(805) 379-2322
Make An Appointment
HomeAbout UsMeet Our ProvidersErik C. Spayde, MDJonathan Rice, MPA, PA-CJason Hartman, DOServicesMinimally Invasive Spine SurgeryArtificial Disc ReplacementVertebroplasty or KyphoplastyXLIF®Epidural Steroid InjectionsStem Cell TherapyImaging Services (MRI)Patient FormsFor SpaydeFor HartmanEducationTestimonialsFrom Patients of Dr. SpaydeTeleMed Consult
